Register of the Joseph Hansen Papers, 1887-1980.
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1928-1978.
  - "The Transition Program: A Guide to the Socialist Society," 1945. Outline notes for speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 2)
  - "The Greek Civil War," 1945 January 7. Outline notes for speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 3)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1945 May 12 (Folder 4)
  - Article on Friedrich A. von Hayek, 1945 June. Typescript (incomplete) (Folder 5)
  - Speech on Albert Goldman, internal SWP meeting, 1945 October 6. Outline notes and partial typescript (Folder 6)
  - Statement on Octavio Fernandez family (with Charles Cornell), 1945 November 17. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - Notes on Greece, ca. 1945-1946 (Folder 8)
  - Speech on Albert Goldman, internal SWP meeting, ca. 1945-1946. Notes (Folder 9)
  - Election campaign speeches as candidate for United States Senate, New York, 1946. Notes (Folder 10)
  - "The Great Frame-Up," 1946. Review of Michael Sayers and Albert E. Kahn, The Great Conspiracy against Russia. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "Internationalism," 1946. Holograph (Folder 12)
  - "Join the Socialist Workers Party," 1946. Outline notes for speech as candidate for United States Senate, New York (Folder 13)
  - Notes on Joseph Stalin, 1946 (Folder 14)
  - "Problems that Face the Workers," 1946. Notes for election campaign speech as candidate for United States Senate, New York (Folder 15)
  - Speech notes and other notes, internal SWP meetings, 1946 (Folder 16)
  - "Transition Demands: A Bridge to the Socialist Society," 1946. Outline notes for speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 17)
  - "Why We Went" (re visit to Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia), 1946. Outline notes for oral report at internal SWP meeting (Folder 18)
  - Notes on Albert Goldman-Felix Morrow faction and Workers Party, ca. 1946 April (Folder 19)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1946 May 19 (Folder 20)
  - "Trotsky's Biography of Stalin," 1946 May 26. Outline notes for speech (Folder 21)
  - "Transition Demands: The Road to a Better World," 1946 June 21. Outline notes for speech (Folder 22)
  - Speech, Indonesia League rally, 1946 August 16. Outline notes (Folder 23)
  - "Trotsky and the Socialist Society of the Future," 1946 August 21. Notes and flyer (Folder 24)
  - "Real Meaning of Nuremberg Trials," 1946 October. Outline notes for speech (Folder 25)
  - "Will We Have War with the Soviet Union?" 1946 October 24. Typescript of election campaign radio address as candidate for United States Senate, New York (Folder 26)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP national convention, 1946 November 15 (Folder 27)
  - "Bourgeois Politics and Workers' Politics in the Face of Imperialism," 1947. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - "Byrnes' Get Tough Policy," 1947. Notes for speech (Folder 29)
  - Speech on socialism, 1947. Outline notes (Folder 30)
  - "Transition Program," 1947. Outline notes for internal SWP speech (Folder 31)
  - Speech on Workers Party, internal SWP meeting, 1947 February. Outline notes (Folder 32)
  - "The Road to Socialism," 1947 May 22. Outline notes for speech, and flyer (Folder 33)
  - "The Path of a Renegade: The Political Evolution of James Burnham," 1947 May 23. Outline notes for speech (with flyer), and typescript version prepared as review of James Burnham, The Struggle for the World (Folder 34)
  - "Marshall Plan," 1947 October 3. Outline notes for speech (Folder 35)
  - Notes on Soviet foreign policy, ca. 1947-1948 (Folder 36)
  - "New Evidence of Stalin's Fear of Trotskyism," 1948. Typescript (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Notes on atomic energy, 1948 (Folder 2)
  - "100th Anniversary of Manifesto, " 1948. Notes (Folder 3)
  - Report on SWP resolution, 1948. Notes for speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 4)
  - "The Socialist Workers Party," 1948. Outline notes for recruiting speech (Folder 5)
  - Speech, internal SWP meeting, 1948. Outline notes (Folder 6)
  - "The Struggle for World Power," 1948. Outline notes for speech (Folder 7)
  - "The Struggle for Power in Europe," lecture tour, 1948 January
    - Outline notes and typescript (Folder 8)
    - Publicity material, schedules, and tour progress report (Folder 9)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1948 February 21 (Folder 10)
  - "Resolution of the Sixth Plenum of the International Executive Committee on 'The Social Struggles in Western Europe since 1944, '" 1948 October. Outline (Folder 11)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP internal debate on Eastern Europe, 1949 (Folder 12)
  - "Scientists and the Atomic Frankenstein," 1949 May. Outline notes for speech (Folder 13)
  - Notes on Bolivia, ca. 1950s (Folder 14)
  - Notes on bureaucracy, ca. 1950s (Folder 15)
  - Notes on Eastern Europe, ca. 1950s (Folder 16)
  - Notes on International Socialist Review, ca. 1950s (Folder 17)
  - Notes on Mark Zborowski, ca. 1950s (Folder 18)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, ca. 1950s (Folder 19)
  - Trotsky School lecture material, ca. 1950s. Typescripts and outlines of lectures; notes; and curricular material. Note: Joseph Hansen was an instructor at the Trotsky School, which was operated by the SWP to train members in Marxist theory
    - Introductory lectures (Folder 20)
    - Dialectics (Folder 21)
    - Fetishism (Folder 22)
    - Marx, Karl, Capital, Volume I
      - General (Folder 23-24)
      - General (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Charts (Folder 2)
      - Money, Lecture material re (Folder 3)
      - Outlines (Folder 4)
      - Review (Folder 5)
      - Chapter 1 (Folder 6-8)
      - Chapter 2 (Folder 9)
      - Chapter 3 (Folder 10-11)
      - Chapter 4 (Folder 12)
      - Chapter 5 (Folder 13)
      - Chapter 6 (Folder 14)
      - Chapter 7 (Folder 15)
      - Chapter 8 (Folder 16)
      - Chapter 9 (Folder 17)
      - Chapter 10 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 11 (Folder 2)
      - Chapter 12 (Folder 3)
      - Chapter 13 (Folder 4)
      - Chapter 14 (Folder 5)
      - Chapter 15 (Folder 6-8)
      - Chapter 16 (Folder 9)
      - Chapter 17 (Folder 10)
      - Chapter 18 (Folder 11)
      - Chapter 19 (Folder 12)
      - Chapter 20 (Folder 13)
      - Chapter 21 (Folder 14)
      - Chapter 22 (Folder 15)
      - Chapter 23 (Folder 16)
      - Chapter 24 (Folder 17)
      - Chapter 25 (Folder 18)
      - Chapter 26 (Folder 19)
      - Chapter 27 (Folder 20)
      - Chapter 28 (Folder 21)
      - Chapter 29 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 30 (Folder 2)
      - Chapter 31 (Folder 3)
      - Chapter 32 (Folder 4)
      - Chapter 33 (Folder 5)
    - Marx, Karl, Capital, Volume II (Folder 6)
    - Marx, Karl, "Introduction to the Critique of Political Economy" (Folder 7)
    - Marx, Karl, Political Economy and Philosophy (Folder 8)
    - Russian Revolution (Folder 9)
    - Miscellany (Folder 10)
  - Election campaign speech as candidate for United States Senate, New York, 1950. Outline notes (Folder 11)
  - Notes on Eastern Europe, 1950 (Folder 12)
  - Notes on Johnson-Forest Tendency, 1950 (Folder 13)
  - "Socialism as Way to Peace," 1950. Outline notes for speech (Folder 14)
  - Speech on Cold War, internal SWP meeting, 1950. Outline notes (Folder 15)
  - Speeches on Soviet foreign policy, internal SWP meetings, 1950. Notes (Folder 16)
  - Speech, SWP National Committee plenum, 1950 February 10. Notes (Folder 17)
  - "World Empire or World Socialism," 1950 July 15. Election campaign radio address as candidate for United States Senate, New York. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "After Korea, What?" 1950 September. Election campaign speech as candidate for United States Senate, New York. Outline notes (Folder 19)
  - Election campaign speech as candidate for United States Senate, New York, 1950 October. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1950 October 13 (Folder 21)
  - Notes on internal SWP situation, 1951 (Folder 22)
  - Reports on SWP press, internal SWP meetings, 1951. Outline notes (Folder 23)
  - Speech on Johnson-Forest Tendency, internal SWP meeting, 1951. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - "America and the World Crisis," lecture tour, 1951 February-April
    - Notes and holograph of standard speech (Folder 25)
    - Debate with Minnesota State Senator Fay George Child, University of Minnesota, 1951 March 14. Notes (Folder 26)
    - "Trotsky the Man," 1951 March 24. Notes for variant speech in Seattle (Folder 27)
    - "Is China a Puppet of Moscow?" 1951 March 27. Notes for variant speech in Seattle (Folder 28)
  - "America and the World Crisis," 1951 February-April (Contd.)
    - Announcements (Folder 29)
    - Clippings (Folder 30)
    - Schedules and miscellany (Folder 31)
  - "Socialism as Way to Peace," 1951 September 30. Typescripts of speech, and flyers (Folder 32)
  - Report on SWP resolution, internal SWP meeting, 1951 December. Notes (Folder 33)
  - Notes on national elections, 1952 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Notes on internal SWP meetings, 1952 (Folder 2)
  - "Shachtman," 1952. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1952 May (Folder 4)
  - "The Steel Crisis and the Trend to Government by Executive Decree," 1952 May 16. Outline notes for speech (Folder 5)
  - "Eisenhower and Fascism," 1952 November. Notes for speech (Folder 6)
  - "Future of American Politics: The Meaning of the 1952 Elections," 1952 November. Outline notes and partial typescript of speech (Folder 7)
  - Notes, ca. 1952-1953 (Folder 8)
  - "France," 1953. Outline notes for speech at internal SWP meeting (Folder 9)
  - Notes for debates with Harry Braverman, internal SWP meetings, 1953 (Folder 10-11)
  - Notes on McCarthyism, 1953 (Folder 12)
  - Notes on internal SWP dispute, 1953 (Folder 13-17)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1953 (Folder 18)
  - "PCI Line" (re Parti Communiste Internationaliste [France]), 1953. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - Summary of Bert Cochran position in internal SWP dispute, 1953. Notes (Folder 20)
  - Notes on Bolivia, 1953 January (Folder 21)
  - Article on internal SWP dispute, 1953 February. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1953 May 28 (Box 48, Folder 1-3)
  - Notes on report by George Clarke at internal SWP meeting, 1953 June 11 (Folder 4)
  - "McCarthy Reaches for the White House," 1953 December. Outline notes for speech (Folder 5)
  - Notes on McCarthyism, 1953 December (Folder 6)
  - Notes on Pabloism, 1953 December (Folder 7)
  - Notes on Isaac Deutscher, 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Notes on Indochina, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - Notes on world situation, 1954 (Folder 10)
  - "The Attempt to Free Trotsky's Killer," 1954 March 15. Notes, typescripts (in English and Spanish), and printed copy (in Spanish) (Folder 11)
  - Debate with Myra Tanner Weiss on race question, internal SWP meeting, 1954 April. Notes (Folder 12)
  - Speech, 70th birthday of Carl Skoglund, 1954 April 7. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - Commencement speech, Trotsky School, 1954 May. Notes (Folder 14)
  - Speech on Guatemala, 1954 July. Outline notes and partial holograph (Folder 15)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP national convention, 1954 November 26-28 (Folder 16)
  - Article on automation, 1955. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - Notes on China, ca. 1955 (Folder 18)
  - "The Problem of Pseudomorphs and the Resurgence of Old Forms in the Revolutionary Process Today," 1955. Notes, holographs, and typescripts (Folder 19)
  - Review of Max Eastman, Reflections on the Failure of Socialism, 1955. Notes and typescript (Folder 20)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1955 September (Folder 21)
  - "Some Problems in Assessing the Chinese Revolution," 1955 September 10
    - Typescript (Folder 22)
    - Mimeographs (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
  - "Verdict of History" (re conflict between Leon Trotsky and Joseph Stalin), 1956. Notes and typescript of speech (Folder 3)
  - "The End of the Stalin Cult," 1956 May 1. Outline notes for speech (Folder 4)
  - Eulogy for John G. Wright, 1956 June 27. Notes (Folder 5)
  - "Report on the Trotsky School," 1956 August. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Discussion on Question of Tactical Approach to Elements Starting to Break with the Stalinists," 1956 October 4. Typed and mimeograph transcripts of discussion with George Novack and other SWP leaders (Folder 7)
  - Notes on Howard Fast, The Naked God, ca. 1957 (Folder 8)
  - The Socialist Workers Party: What It Is, What It Stands For, revised edition, 1957
    - Printed copy of first edition (1948) annotated to indicate changes (Folder 9)
    - Typescript (Folder 10)
  - Speech on Leon Trotsky, Stanford University, 1957. Outline notes (Folder 11)
  - "Stalinism," 1957. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - Election campaign speech as candidate for mayor of Los Angeles, 1957 March 8. Notes (Folder 13)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1957 April (Folder 14)
  - "The Outlook for Socialist Regroupment," lecture tour, 1957 April-May. Outline notes and publicity material (Folder 15)
  - "Four Forgotten Congresses of Lenin's Time" (re first four World Congresses of Communist International), 1957 September. Notes for lecture series at SWP West Coast vacation school (Folder 16-18)
  - Letter to the editor, The Militant, re Howard Fast, 1957 December 1. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "The Method of Historical Materialism," 1957 December 6. Notes for debate with Professor Leonard Ascher in San Francisco, and announcement (Folder 20)
  - Notes for debate with Sam Marcy, internal SWP meeting, 1958 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1958 (Folder 2)
  - Speech on regroupment, SWP New York City branch, 1958. Outline notes (Folder 3)
  - Speech on Leon Trotsky, Stanford University, 1958. Notes (Folder 4)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1958 January 24 (Folder 5)
  - Notes on Charles de Gaulle, 1958 June (Folder 6)
  - Speech on Charles de Gaulle, internal SWP meeting, 1958 July 2. Outline notes (Folder 7)
  - Speech on American-Soviet summit conferences, internal SWP meeting, 1958 August. Outline notes (Folder 8)
  - Speech on Trotsky School, SWP New York City branch, 1958 November 6. Notes (Folder 9)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1958 November 27 (Folder 10)
  - Notes on China, ca. 1959 (Folder 11)
  - "Will E[isenhower] Accept K[hrushchev]'s Disarmament Offer?" 1959. Notes for speech (Folder 12)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP national convention, 1959 June 26-28 (Folder 13)
  - Notes on United Independent Socialist Committee meeting, New York City, 1959 September 26 (Folder 14)
  - Notes on population explosion, ca. 1959-1961 (Folder 15)
  - "Mandel's Marxist Economic Theory, " ca. 1960s. Holograph (Folder 16)
  - "Notes for Memo on Greece," ca. 1960s. Notes (Folder 17)
  - Notes on Cuba, ca. 1960s (Folder 18)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, ca. 1960s (Folder 19)
  - Preface to proposed new edition of Leon Trotsky, In Defense of Marxism, ca. 1960s. Notes and typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Revolutionary Strategy and Tactics," ca. 1960s. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - Notes on George Novack, The Long View of History, ca. 1960 (Folder 22)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1960 February 26-28 (Folder 23)
  - Notes on trip to Cuba, 1960 April (Folder 24)
  - Speech, birthday celebration for Carl Skoglund, 1960 April 7? (year uncertain). Holograph (Folder 25)
  - Radio address on Cuba, 1960 April 29. Typescript (Folder 26)
  - Notes on SWP regional conference, Chicago, 1960 July 23 (Folder 27)
  - "On Cuba," 1960 October 7. Notes (Folder 28)
  - "Should Socialists Join Battle for Reforms?" The Militant, 1960 October 17. Printed copy (Folder 29)
  - "More on Why Socialists Struggle for Reforms," The Militant, 1960 November 21. Printed copy (Folder 30)
  - "Cuba vs. A[lliance] for P[rogress]," 1961. Outline notes for speech (Folder 31)
  - Notes on Theodore Draper, Castro's Cuba, 1961 (Folder 32)
  - Speeches on Cuba, 1961. Notes (Folder 33)
  - "Theory of the Cuban Revolution," International Socialist Review, 1961 Winter. Typed, mimeographed and printed copies of Spanish translation (Folder 34)
  - "What Makes Latin America Explosive?" 1961. Notes for speech (Folder 35)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1961 January 13-14 (Folder 36)
  - Notes on Conferencia Latinoamericana por la Soberania Nacional, la Emancipacion Economica y la Paz, Mexico City, 1961 March 5-8 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Speech on Conferencia Latinoamericana por la Soberania Nacional, la Emancipacion Economica y la Paz, 1961 March 11. Notes and announcements (Folder 3)
  - "Debate on Cuban Question," 1961 March 30. Notes and typescript of speech at internal SWP branch meeting (Folder 4)
  - Notes on internal SWP New York City branch debate on Cuba, 1961 April-May (Folder 5)
  - Notes on Vicente Lombardo Toledano, 1961 June (Folder 6)
  - Speech notes and other notes, internal SWP New York City branch debate on Cuba, 1961 June 1-8 (Folder 7)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP national convention, 1961 June 22 (Folder 8)
  - "The Theory of the Permanent Revolution," 1961 June 30. Outline notes, typescript, and typed transcript of internal SWP lecture (Folder 9)
  - "Permanent Revolution in Cuba," 1961 July 1. Outline notes, typescript, and typed transcript of internal SWP lecture (Folder 10)
  - "Latin America," 1961 July 2. Outline notes for internal SWP lecture (Folder 11)
  - "Cuba," ca. 1961 August. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - Notes on tour of Latin America, 1961 September-1962 January (Folder 13-14)
  - Notes on Latin America, ca. 1962 (Folder 15)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1962 (Folder 16)
  - "Reply to Hoy, " 1962. Typescript (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Eulogy for Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia, 1962 January 29. Biographical data on Trotskaia, notes, and typescript (Folder 2)
  - Discussion with Socialist Labour League (Great Britain) National Executive Committee, 1962 February 3-4. Mimeograph transcript (Folder 3)
  - "What Makes Latin America Explosive," lecture tour, 1962 February-June
    - Notes and partial typescript of standard speech (Folder 4)
    - Notes on tour (Folder 5)
    - Letter to the editor, The Militant, re tour, 1962 April 30. Holograph and printed copy (Folder 6)
    - Announcements (Folder 7)
    - Clippings (Folder 8-9)
    - Reports on tour from SWP local branches (Folder 10)
    - Schedules, receipts and miscellany (Folder 11)
  - Report and notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1962 June 14-17
    - Notes, typescript and mimeograph of majority international report (Folder 12)
    - Notes on plenum (Folder 13)
  - "Bank Holdup in Peru," The Militant, 1962 August 13. Typescript. Includes typed translation of accompanying statement by robbers (Folder 14)
  - "Algeria," 1962 August 19. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Chiang," 1962 August 20. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - " L'Express on Cuba," ca. 1962 September. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Algiers," 1962 September 3. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Algeria," 1962 September 15. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Algeria," 1962 September 21. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Alistair Cooke," 1962 October. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - "It Was Reported in the Press," 1962 October. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - "Cuba, the Acid Test: A Reply to the Ultraleft Sectarians," 1962 November 20. Mimeograph and fragment of typescript (Folder 23)
  - "Algerian Appeal for Help," 1962 December. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - "Algerian Govt. Sets Example," 1962 December. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - "Algerians Acclaim Steps toward Socialism," ca. 1962-1963. Typescript (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - "Balance Sheet of the French Mine Strike," ca. 1962-1963. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - Shorthand notes on meeting with Gerry Healy, ca. 1962-1963 (Folder 3)
  - "What Algeria's Children Face," ca. 1962-1963. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The 'New Frontier' in South Vietnam," ca. 1963. Holograph (Folder 5)
  - Notes on Brazil, 1963 (Folder 6)
  - Article on demonstration of unemployed in London, 1963 March 27. Holograph (Folder 7)
  - "Algeria," 1963 April. Typescripts (Folder 8)
  - "Algerian CP," 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Algiers Demonstration," 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "French Committee Formed to Aid Algeria," 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "French Dissemble Anger over Seizures," 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "French Pressure on Algeria," 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Management Committees" (re Algeria), 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Monopoly Foreign Trade" (re Algeria), 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "New Stage" (re Algeria), 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "Slogans" (re Algeria), 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Turn in Algeria Wins Support of Communists," 1963 April. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Aid for Algeria," 1963 May. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Algeria," 1963 May. Typescripts (Folder 20)
  - "Italy," 1963 May. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - "'Help the New Algeria!'" 1963 June 20. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - "Trotskyist Movement Reunited," 1963 June 27. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - Report and notes, SWP national convention, 1963 July 18-21
    - Typescript of international report (Folder 24)
    - Notes (Folder 25)
  - "Healy," 1964. Notes and typescript (Folder 26)
  - "Reply" (re George Breitman views of Isaac Deutscher), 1964 February. Typescript (Folder 27)
  - "Le Monde Declares Oswald Photo Was Faked," 1964 April 23. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - Notes on Maurice Thorez, 1964 July (Folder 29)
  - Notes and fragments on Algeria, 1965 (Folder 30)
  - Notes on question of Fourth International statutes, 1965 (Folder 31)
  - Notes on SWP press, 1965 (Folder 32)
  - "The Trotsky Anthology," 1965. Review of The Age of Permanent Revolution: A Trotsky Anthology. Typescript (Folder 33)
  - "Bosch Interview in Marcha, " 1966. Typescript (Folder 34)
  - Notes on Pierre Frank, Pablo's Break with the Fourth International, 1966 (Folder 35)
  - Notes on Soviet critique of Trotskyism, 1966 (Folder 36)
  - Notes on United Secretariat draft resolution, 1966 (Folder 37)
  - Notes on world situation, 1966 (Folder 38)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1966 (Folder 39)
  - "Suggested Changes in Draft of Political Resolution [of United Secretariat]," 1966 January. Typescript (Folder 40)
  - "In Answer to Castro's Attack on 'Trotskyism, '" The Militant, 1966 January 31. Notes, printed copy, and mimeograph Spanish translation (Folder 41)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1966 February 11-12 (Folder 42)
  - "The Case against 'Pacification, '" International Socialist Review, 1966 Fall. Printed copy (Folder 43)
  - Eulogy for Ethel Preis, 1966 November 14. Typescript (Folder 44)
  - International report, SWP National Committee plenum, 1966 November 18-20. Typescript. Includes notes on plenum (Folder 45)
  - Introduction to Che Guevara Speaks, 1967. Notes and typescript (Folder 46)
  - "Is Marxism-Leninism Obsolete?" 1967. Notes and typescripts (Folder 47)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1967 (Folder 48)
  - "The OLAS Conference: Tactics and Strategy for a Continental Revolution," 1967. Typescript (Folder 49)
  - "The Upheaval in China: An Analysis of the Contending Forces," The Militant, 1967 January 23. Mimeograph Spanish translation (Folder 50)
  - Notes on antiwar conference, Chicago, 1967 May 20 (Folder 51)
  - Speech, SWP National Committee plenum, 1967 June 2. Outline notes (Folder 52)
  - Notes on arrangements to visit Cuba, 1967 June 30-July 3 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Article on arrest of Daniel Camejo and others, Mexico City, 1967 July 20. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "Torture Used on 13 Victims of Witch-hunt in Mexico," 1967 July 22. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Article on arrest of Daniel Camejo and others, Mexico City, 1967 July 24. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "On the Eve of the OLAS Conference," 1967 July 30. Holograph and typescripts (Folder 5)